

SKILLS

ABILITIES

Proactive
Empathetic
Responsible
Logical thinking
Analytical skills
Attention to detail
Teamwork
Leadership

LANGUAGES

Advanced English Spanish

STUDYING

Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate, Coursera

Azure Infra Girls, Microsoft Reactor

OTHER DATA

Valid Mexican and Spanish passports Valid visa

Carlotta Rivera Alcalde

DATA ANALYSIS ENTHUSIAST - MECHATRONIC ENGINEER

carlottariveraalcalde@gmail.com

(+52) 477-5816697

in linkedin.com/in/carlotta-rivera-alcalde-82b49724a

México City

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Mechatronic engineer, undergraduate from Universidad Iberoamericana de León. Experienced in data analysis applied to logistics, with extensive knowledge in SQL and advanced english proficiency. Proactive, tenacious, with logical thinking and a fast learner, and a particular passion for technology.

Looking for an opportunity to join a global company where I can grow, learn, and contribute enthusiastically.

AREAS OF INTEREST

Data Analysis, Data Science, Automation, SQL, PLC Programming, Python, Business Management.

EDUCATION

Mechatronic Engineering, Universidad Iberoamericana de León

August 2019 — July 2024

Academic Excellence Award for a GPA of 9.4

- Relevant courses: Database Design and Querying, Project Management, Production, Financial Analysis.
- Programmed a robotic arm and presented it at the Hannover Messe fair to inspire young people to explore
 the field of robotics.

WORK HISTORY

Intern at Ecodeli, León, Gto.

November 2023 — April 2024

- Designed SQL queries to identify, audit, and optimize logistics processes.
- Cleaned and maintained data on purchases, sales, and costs.
- Kept in constant communication with different departments.

Achievements:

- Designed a daily report prioritizing by urgency and client level, optimizing delivery logistics.
- Identified the source and impact of high operating costs.
- Cleaned and updated the system for 500+ loan contracts, allowing sales projections to be adjusted to reflect reality.

Volunteer at Casa del Sol, Puebla

August 2018 — June 2019

- · Assisted in daily care and activities.
- Managed various events, including recreational and fundraising activities.

Skills Developed:

- Problem-solving under pressure.
- Dynamic and assertive communication.
- Leadership and positive influence among peers.

INTERNATIONAL EXPERIENCE

Universidad Loyola Andalucía, Seville

January 2023 — June 2023

- Highly significant for introducing me to database design and querying methods.
- The Organizational Management course was taught in English, with classmates from various countries and cultures.

Skills Developed:

- Maturity in decision-making and problem-solving.
- · Gained fluency in everyday English.

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Service at Equitach, San Cristóbal de las Casas

May 2022 — July 2022

Equine therapy center for children with disabilities.

• Gained experience in managing and organizing daily activities, as well as larger-scale events with increased responsibility.



COMPETENCIAS

Microsoft Excel SQL

Python
Intelisis

Portal TIA
C++

Power BI
Azure

Tableau

RStudio

Bases de Datos

HABILIDADES

Proactiva
Empática
Responsable
Pensamiento lógico
Capacidad de análisis
Atención al detalle
Trabajo en equipo
Liderazgo

IDIOMAS

Inglés Avanzado Español

CURSANDO

Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate, Coursera

Azure Infra Girls, Microsoft Reactor

OTROS DATOS

Pasaporte Mexicano y Españo vigentes Visa vigente

Carlotta Rivera Alcalde

ENTUSIASTA DE ANÁLISIS DE DATOS - ING. MECATRÓNICA

carlottariveraalcalde@gmail.com

(+52) 477-5816697

in linkedin.com/in/carlotta-rivera-alcalde-82b49724a

Ciudad de México

PERFIL PROFESIONAL

Ingeniera mecatrónica, recién egresada de la Universidad Iberoamericana de León. Con experiencia en análisis de datos aplicados a logística, amplio conocimiento en SQL y manejo avanzado de inglés. Proactiva, tenaz, de pensamiento lógico y rápido aprendizaje, un gusto particular por la tecnología.

En búsqueda de una oportunidad en una empresa trasnacional donde desarrollarme, aprender y aportar con entusiasmo.

CAMPOS DE INTERÉS

Análisis de datos, Ciencia de datos, Automatización, SQL, programación de PLC, Python, Gestión de negocios.

EDUCACIÓN

Ingeniería Mecatrónica, Universidad Iberoamericana de León

Agosto 2019 — Julio 2024

Reconocimiento de excelencia académica por promedio de 9.4

- Clases relevantes: Diseño y consulta de base de datos, Gestión de Proyectos, Producción, Análisis Financiero.
- Programación de un brazo robótico y presentación en la feria Hannover Messe para atraer a jóvenes al área de robótica.

EXPERIENCIA LABORAL

Practicante en Ecodeli, León, Gto.

Noviembre 2023 — Abril 2024

- Auditorías y consultas SQL, para identificar y optimizar procesos de logística.
- Limpieza y mantenimiento de datos de compras, ventas y costos.
- Comunicación constante con los diferentes departamentos.

Logros

- Diseño de reporte diario, priorizando por urgencia y nivel de cliente, que optimizó la logística de entregas.
- Identificación de origen y consecuencia de costos operativos elevados.
- Depuración y actualización de sistema de 500+ contratos de comodato, que permitió ajustar las proyecciones de venta a la realidad.

Voluntariado en Casa del Sol, Puebla

Agosto 2018 — Junio 2019

- Colaboración en cuidado y actividades diarias.
- Gestión de eventos varios; recreativos y de recaudación de fondos.

Habilidades desarrollas

- Resolución de problemas bajo presión.
- Comunicación dinámica y asertiva.
- Liderazgo e influencia positiva entre mis compañeras.

EXPERIENCIA INTERNACIONAL

Universidad Lovola Andalucía, Sevilla

Enero 2023 — Junio 2023

- Altamente significativa por introducirme el diseño y método de consulta de base de datos.
- El curso de Gestión Organizacional se impartió en inglés, con compañeros de distintos países y culturas.

Habilidades desarrolladas

- Madurez en toma de decisiones y solución de imprevistos.
- Fluidez en el manejo cotidiano del inglés.

ACTIVIDADES EXTRACURRICULARES

Servicio en Equitach, San Cristóbal de las Casas

Mayo 2022 — Julio 2022

Centro de equino-terapia para niños con discapacidades.

 Consolidé experiencia en gestión y organización de actividades diarias y eventos a mayor escala y con mayor nivel de responsabilidad.